Guide to the Samuel A. Elliot collection,1927-1935.
Elliot, Samuel A. collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Samuel A. Elliot collection, 1927-1935.
9165
Samuel A., Elliot.
1.2 cu ft.
Legal documents, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Contains reports to the Board of Indian commissioners, reports 1-107, bulletins regarding Indians to the 70th Congress, and bulletins from the American Indian Defense Association, Inc. The items are typed mimeos. Indexes for the 70th Congress and American Indian Defense association papers and for the Indian Commissioners reports are included. Various authors. A wide variety of topics are covered including Indian and government relations, land tenure, living conditions, laws, and government programs. Focus on western United States Indian communities, reservations, and tribes including, Pueblo, Apache, Navajo, Salish, Cherokee, and Dakota. Agency reports from Sac and Fox, Winnebago, Pima, Consolidated Chippewa, Rocky Boy, St. Regis, Yakima, Western Shoshone, and San Carlos Indian agencies and reservations. Authors include Flora Warren Seymour, Hugh L. Scott, Earl Y. Henderson, Mary Vaux Walcott, Clement S. Ucker and John J. Sullivan.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Contains reports to the Board of Indian commissioners, reports 1-107, bulletins regarding Indians to the 70th Congress, and bulletins from the American Indian Defense Association, Inc. The items are typed mimeos. Indexes for the 70th Congress and American Indian Defense association papers and for the Indian Commissioners reports are included. Various authors. A wide variety of topics are covered including Indian and government relations, land tenure, living conditions, laws, and government programs. Focus on western United States Indian communities, reservations, and tribes including, Pueblo, Apache, Navajo, Salish, Cherokee, and Dakota. Agency reports from Sac and Fox, Winnebago, Pima, Consolidated Chippewa, Rocky Boy, St. Regis, Yakima, Western Shoshone, and San Carlos Indian agencies and reservations. Authors include Flora Warren Seymour, Hugh L. Scott, Earl Y. Henderson, Mary Vaux Walcott, Clement S. Ucker and John J. Sullivan.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Elliot, Samuel A.; Henderson, Earl Y.; Scott, Hugh Lenox, 1853-1934.; Seymour, Flora Warren,1888-1948.; Sullivan, John J.; Ucker, Clement S.; Walcott, Mary Vaux,1860-1940.; American Indian Defense Association.; United States.Board of Indian Commissioners.; United States.Congress(70th, 1st session :1928-1929).; United States.Congress(70th, 2nd session :1928-1929).; United States.Office of Indian Affairs.Consolidated Chippewa Agency.; United States.Office of Indian Affairs.Umatilla Agency.; United States.Office of Indian Affairs.Western Shoshone Agency.; United States.Office of Indian Affairs.Winnebago Agency.; Huntington Free Library.
Subjects:
Indians of North America.; Indians of North America Education.; Indians of North America Government relations.; Indians of North America Land tenure.; Indians of North America Social conditions.; Indians of North America West (U.S.).; Indian reservations.; Apache Indians.; Cherokee Indians.; Dakota Indians.; Navajo Indians.; Pima Indians.; Pueblo Indians.; Salish Indians.; Seminole Indians.; Skitswish Indians.
Places:
Rocky Boy's Reservation (Mont.).; Sac and Fox Reservation (Iowa).; Saint Regis Mohawk Indian Reservation (N.Y.).; San Carlos Indian Reservation (Ariz.).; Yakama Indian Reservation (Wash.).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Original Huntington Free Library box numbers have been retained. Box contains multiple unrelated collections. Folder numbers pertain to this specific collection only and are not folder order for the entire box.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Board of Indian Commissioners reports
Boxes 5A-5E
Series II. 70th Congress bulletins
Box 46, Folders 9165-1 - 9165-3
Series III. American Indian Defense Association, Inc. papers
Box 46, Folders 9165-4 - 9165-12
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Board of Indian Commissioners reports
  - Numbers 1-21, January 1928 - November 1928
    - 1. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Havasupai Indian Agency, Arizona., January 30, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 2. Henderson, Earl Y. Report of the Truxton Canyon Indian Agency, Arizona., February 1, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 3. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Colorado River Indian Agency and the Fort Mojave Indian School, Arizona., March 7, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 4. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Fort Yuma Indian Agency, California., April 14, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 5. The problem of Indian administration., May 21, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 6. The problem of Indian administration., May 25, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 7. The problem of Indian administration., May 27, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 8. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Report on the Zuni Indian Reservation, New Mexico., June 25, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 9. Walcott, Mary Vaux Needs of the Supai Indians of Arizona., June 26, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 10. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the New York Indians., June 30, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 11. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Navajo schools and hospitals., July 10, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 12 Walcott, Mary Vaux. Report on the Paiute Indian Agency, Utah., July 15, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 13. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the Carson School and Agency, Nevada., August 4, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 14. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the California Indians., August 15, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 15. Scott, Hugh L. The Mille Lac Chippewa., August 19, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 16. Seymour, Fora Warren. Report on Northern Pueblo Indians, New Mexico., August 25, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 17. Scott, Hugh L. The Blackfeet Agency, Montana., September 25, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 18. Scott, Hugh L. Pipestone Indian School., October 25, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 19. Scott, Hugh L. Cheyenne River Agency, South Dakota., October 26, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 20. Scott, Hugh L. Standing Rock Agency, North Dakota., October 30, 1928 (Box 5A)
    - 21. Sullivan, John J. Indian Schools in Michigan., November 1, 1928 (Box 5A)
  - Numbers 22-42, November 1928 - October 1929
    - 22. Sullivan, John J. The Hayward School. Wisconsin., November 2, 1928 (Box 5B)
    - 23. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Neah Bay Indian Agency, Washington., January 7, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 24. Report of Board of Indian Commissioners on "The Problem of Indian Administration.", January 10, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 25. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Taholah Indian Agency, Washington., January 25, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 26. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Tulalip Indian Agency, Washington., February 14, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 27. Ucker, Clement S. Report on the Seminole Indians of Florida., May 26, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 28. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Report on the Klamath Reservation, Oregon., August 4, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 29. Scott, Hugh L. Fort Peck Agency, Montana., August 5, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 30. Mooreliead, Warren K. Report upon conditions, St.. Regis Reservation, northern New York., August 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 31. Scott, Hugh L. Report on the Blackfeet Indians, Montana., August 22, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 32. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Report on the Mission Indians and Sherman Institute., September 15, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 33. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Report on the California Outing Centers., September 25, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 34. Scott Hugh L. The Flathead Agency, Montana., September 26, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 35. Scott, Hugh L. Crow Agency, Montana., September 26, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 36. Scott, Hugh L. Shoshone Arapaho Indians, Wyoming., September 26, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 37. Scott, Hugh L. Fort Hall Indian Agency, Idaho., September 28, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 38. Walcott, Mary Vaux. California and Nevada Indians., October 1, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 39. Moorehead, Warren K. Conditions on St. Regis Reservation, New York., October 1, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 40. Scott, Hugh L. Rocky Boy Agency, Montana., October 7, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 41. Seymour, Flora Warren. Coeur d'Alene Indians, Idaho., October 10, 1929 (Box 5B)
    - 42. Seymour, Flora Warren. The situation at Umatilla., October 28, 1929 (Box 5B)
  - Numbers 43-63, October 1929 - August 1930
    - 43. Seymour, Flora Warren. Yakima Agency, Washington., October 29, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 44. Seymour, Flora Warren. Concerning Chemawa's future., October 30, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 45. Seymour, Flora Warren. California Indians vs. The United States., November 14, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 46. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the non-reservation Indians under the Carson Agency, Nevada., November 27, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 47. Sullivan, John J. Winnebago Indian Agency, Nebraska., December 27, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 48. Sullivan, John J. Sac and Fox Agency Sanatorium, Iowa., December 28, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 49. Sullivan, John J. Consolidated Chippewa Agency, Minnesota., December 30, 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 50. Sullivan, John J. Red Lake Chippewa Agency, Minnesota., December 31. 1929 (Box 5C)
    - 51. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Walker River Indian Agency, Nevada., January 10. 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 52. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Western Shoshone Indian Reservation., February 25, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 53. Ucker, Clement S. Report on the Pima Indian Agency, Arizona., March 29, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 54. Ucker, Clement S. Report on the San Carlos Indian Reservation, the Phoenix School and Salt River Subagency. Arizona., April 5, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 55. Lindquist, G. E. E. Fort Totten Indian School, North Dakota., May 15, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 56. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Wahpeton Indian School, Wahpeton, North Dakota., May 24, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 57. Lindquist, G. E. E. Fort Berthold Agency, North Dakota., May 29, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 58. Lindquist, G. E. E. Bismarck Indian School, North Dakota., May 31, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 59. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on education among the Eastern Cherokee Indians of North Carolina., June 18, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 60. Ucker, Clement S. Report on the Seminole Indians of Florida., July 9, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 61. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Rocky Boy and Fort Belknap Agencies, Montana., August 1, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 62. Scott, Hugh L. Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota., August 2, 1930 (Box 5C)
    - 63. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Lac du Flambeau Indian Agency, Wisconsin., August 13, 1930 (Box 5C)
  - Numbers 64-84, August 1930 - July 1931
    - 64. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Lac Courts Indian Oreille Indian Reservation and the Hayward School, Wisconsin., August 20, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 65. Seymour, Flora Warren. Tongue River (northern Cheyenne) Reservation, Montana., September 1, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 66. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Winnebago Indians of Wisconsin., September 2, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 67. Seymour, Flora Warren. Shoshone (Wind River) Agency, Wyoming., September 4, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 68. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report the Laona Subagency and Indian Clinic, Wisconsin., September 5, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 69. Seymour, Flora Warren. The Crow Agency, Montana., September 7, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 70. Seymour, Flora Warren. Teaching Indian boys to raise livestock., September 4, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 71. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Lac du Flambeau Indian Agency, Wisconsin., September 23, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 72. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Pierre School, Pierre, South Dakota., September 27, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 73. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Rapid City School, South Dakota., September 27, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 74. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Pipestone and Flandreau Schools., October 18, 1930 (Box 5D)
    - 75. Tribal Council, Klamath Indians, Klamath Agency, Oregon., February 3, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 76. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Paiute Indian Agency, Utah., February 24, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 77. Henderson, Earl Y. Report on the Sells Indian Agency, Arizona., April 20, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 78. Scott, Hugh L. Report on the Pawnee and Quapaw Indian Agencies, Oklahoma., June 10, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 79. Scott, Hugh L. Report on Haskell Institute, Lawrence, Kansas., June 10, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 80. Seymour, Flora Warren. Notes on the Alaskan situations., June 17, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 81. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the Tulalip Indian Agency and the Tacoma Hospital., Washington. June 30, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 82. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the Warm Springs Indian Reservation., June 30, 1931 (Box 5D)
    - 83. Seymour, Flora Warren. Colville Agency, Washington., June 30, 1931. (Box 5D)
    - 84. Scott, Hugh L. Rapid City School, South Dakota., July 22, 1931 (Box 5D)
  - Numbers 85-107, August 1931 - November 1932 and undated
    - 85. Lowndes, Charles H. T. Indian medical service among Pueblo, Zuni, Hopi and Navajo., August 14, 1931 (Box 5E)
    - 86. Lindquist, G. E. E. Consolidated Ute Indian Agency, Ignacio, Colorado., December 23, 1931 (Box 5E)
    - 87. Lowndes, Charles H. T. Health activities among the Pueblo, Zuni, Hopi and Navajo Indians., [undated]
    - 88. Sullivan, John J. Report on the California Indians., January 6, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 89. Lindquist, G. E. E. Jicarilla Apache Reservation, Dulce., January 12, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 90. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report the Kiowa Indian Agency Oklahoma., April 25, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 91. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the Mescalero Indian Reservation, New Mexico., June 6, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 92. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the San Carlos Reservation., June 13, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 93. Lowndes, Charles H.T. Report on the health activities of the Indian service in the southwest., June 16, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 94. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on the Pima Indian Agency, Arizona., June 22, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 95. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Annual Extension Conference, Salem Indian School, Chemawa, Oregon. June 6-8, 1932, June 28, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 96. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Tacoma Indian Hospital, Tacoma, Washington., June 29, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 97. Walcott, Mary Vaux. Report on the Chilocco, Haskell and Genoa Indian Schools, the Winnebago Agency and the Sac and Fox Sanatorium., June 30, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 98. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Taholah Indian Agency, Washington., July 15, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 99. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Neah Bay Indian Agency, Washington., July 16, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 100. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Tulalip Indian Agency, Washington., July 18, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 101. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Yakima Indian Reservation., July 19, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 102. Seymour, Flora Warren. Indian Service Educational Activities in the Southwest., July 28, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 103. Seymour, Flora Warren. Report on Indians in eastern Canada., August 26, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 104. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Fort Hall Indian Agency, Idaho., August 27, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 105. Scott, Hugh L. [untitled] addressed Browning, Montana., August 27, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 106. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Crow Creek Indian Agency, South Dakota., November 16, 1932 (Box 5E)
    - 107. Lindquist, G. E. E. Report on the Osage Indian Agency, Oklahoma., [undated] (Box 5E)
- Series II. 70th Congress bulletins
  - Guide (Box 46, Folder 9165-1)
  - No. 5. The state and the Indians., December 22, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 6. "Orgies of Indian Extravagance, wild and fantastic.", December 23, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 8. Need for immediate action on the California court of claims H.R. 491., December 31. 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 10. The Indian death rate still rising-what the new census tables disclose., January 9, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 11. Indian Bureau Expenditures - States of Montana and North Dakota., January 10, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 12. The Flathead water-power site amendment to the pending appropriation bill., January 12, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 13. Defeat this bureau scheme for confiscating Indian powers., January 12, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 14. What is meant by "commercial value of a power site"?, January 12, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 15. State cooperation in Indian welfare-some misunderstandings corrected., January 23, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 16. Shall the Indian bureau continue to block the development of the Flathead power site?, January 23 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 17. A new assault against Indian water-power rights, The Carlos Apaches are the victims in the pending appropriation bill., January 25, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 18. Value of the Flathead power sites., January 27, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 20. An Indian tribal governor made spokesman for the Indian Bureau., January 31, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 21. Confiscating the Apache water-power site-will the senate commit this action?, February 1, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 22. The renewed attack against Indian ownership of executive order reservations., February 2, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 23. The attack against the Carlos Apache ...Interior Department Bill., February 3, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-2)
  - No. 9-A The proof that Indian welfare effort succeeds and the justification for a new appeal for aid., February 20 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - To the press of New Mexico: position of the American Indian Defense Association on the middle Rio Conservancy Bill., February 25, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - The Rio Grande Conservancy Bill (Pueblo) correction of a mis-statement and some important new facts., February 27, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - No. 25. Now the Senate knows the issues in the Conservancy Bill, S.700., February 28, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - Arabian Nights argument for the Pueblo Conservancy Bill S.700: total errors statement regarding water priorities and taxation., February 29, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - No. 26. The president's veto has been asked for the Pueblo Conservancy Bill., March 6, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - No. 27. Fifty Jackson Barnett cases coming safe from court accounting (HR 7204)., May 10, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - re Pueblo Appropriation in Deficiency Bill., May 21, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - The crisis of the Pueblo Indians explanatory statement accompanying copies of documents by Mr. Louis Marshall, attorney for the Pueblo tribes., May 22, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
  - The Indian Bureau's Conservancy scheme is finally exposed., December 21, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-3)
- Series III. American Indian Defense Association, Inc. papers
  - Guide (Box 46, Folder 9165-4)
  - Letter to Pueblo tribal officials., November 22, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Written statement to the "Oakland Forum"., December 14, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Secretary Work confirms the "Irresponsible Propaganda" and light starts to break on Indian affairs., December 16, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Letter to the members Congress., December 20, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - The hidden crisis in forestry situation., January 4, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Letter to Senator Smoot., January 19, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Letter to the officers of the New Mexico Pueblos., January 21, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Letter to members of U.S. Senate in regard to pending vote on Flathead power-site (2 copies)., February 2, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - The money stake of the Indians in the Flathead Power-site lease controversy., February 6, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - "Recall this bill and protect Pueblo Indians"! (Senate Bill 700)., February 8, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - To the members of the Senate "Broken faith with the Indians and a trick upon Congress", the Pueblo Conservancy Bill (S.700)., February 9, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Rio Grande Pueblo Conservancy., February 11, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - To Senators: the Pueblo outrage which jeopardizes all Indians., February 12, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Rio Grande Conservancy Bill sent back to committee., February 13, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Does the language divert the Flathead Indian revenues?, February 14, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - To the members of the House and Senate: the Cramton Pueblo Conservancy outrage., February 16, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - To the officials of the Pueblos: the Conservancy Bill., February 17, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Statement by John Collier and A. A. Grorud, dealing with certain statements by representative Louis C. Cramton, made on the floor of the House, February 16, 1928., February 17, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - To the members of congress: the acknowledged facts which condemn the pending Rio Grande Pueblo Conservancy Bill., February 19, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - To the several newspapers associations: Middle Rio Grande Pueblo Conservancy Bill., February 22, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Mary Austin declares amended Pueblo Conservancy Bill a menace to the Indians and to the Spanish-American white farmers of New Mexico, February 23, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - A final plea to the Senate on behalf of the Pueblo Indians and of simple national honor., February 24, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - "Has the Pueblo irrigated acreage been shrinking within historic times"?, February 29, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-5)
  - Bulletin No. 1 of series "Conservancy and reclamation on Indian Lands"; "The nightmare of Indian Bureau reclamation and Conservancy,"., January 19, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Fictions and mysteries of the Indian Bureau. Presented by the Bureau of Officers to the Committees of Congress. Haskell Institute Farm Mystery., January 21, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Summary report on the Crow Reservation Irrigation scandal., January 22, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Part of the Indian office record before Congress with respect to the irrigation project on the Crow Reservation., January 22, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Bulletin No. 2 of series, "Conservancy and reclamation of Indian lands", The Fort Belknap, Montana irrigation fiasco and the Indian deceit with respect to it., January 23, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Bulletin No. 3 of series "Conservancy and reclamation of Indian lands", The Fort Peck irrigation collapse., January 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Indian Bureau misrepresentations to Congress with respect to its expenditures on the Crow Reservation., January 26, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - To the members of the House of Representatives., January 29, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Do Indian children slowly starve?., January 30, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Fast and loose goes the Ute Indian money., January 30, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - The Indian Bureau's renewed battle against reform and its whitewash venture of February 1, 1929., February 2,1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Apache Indians and the Senate investigation., February 5,1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - The Indian Bureau's thirty one million dollar joy ride in the guise of reclamation enterprises., February 7, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Governor New Mexico committee ...in the matter of Indian boarding schools., February 9, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Indian boarding schools and the Santa Fe New Mexican., February 11, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Three propaganda statements about Indian boarding schools., February 16, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - A statistician to the rescue., February 20, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - The Fort Mojave school record and the Bureau's new propaganda., February 28, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Suggestions concerning future Indian policy, legislation, and administration., April 22, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - The meeting of the council of all the New Mexico Pueblos., September 2, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - Items of the Indian Defense program-Winter of 1929-1930., November 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)